So let's take a moment to talk about shame and the efficacy of shame.
Now, the truth is that there has been a real effort to make internalized shame about things
that you should not be shameful about a thing, a way of using control.
So we have seen, of course, indigenous people and black people all over the world, given
this idea of internalized shame of who they are as a person, which is a way for them to
be weaponized, to push agendas that actually continue to harm them.
We know that we have seen women continuously shamed for a myriad of reasons, again, to
make them easily controlled.
However, just like so many other words, shame has a multitude of meanings and uses.
And when we talk about public shame and public scorn for problematic actions to the public,
I think shame ends up being something that we can make use of.
Now, I know there are folks that feel themselves to be on a higher vibration by saying, no,
we should never deploy shame.
And of course, you have the right to have that opinion.
However, I know that when people are publicly shamed for behaving in actions that the public
has normalized, it begins a very necessary process of the denormalizing of practices,
behaviors, and harm.
Let's see some examples of public shaming that I believe are very necessary.
The indigenous sun god hates you!
I saw his eyeballs!
Milk, bitch!
Mm-hmm.
They gonna cry in the car.
I don't think shame is a bad motivator at all.
I think it's so effective that the overculture got us not to do it because there's so much
complicity people should be ashamed of.
And to atone for it would require them to dismantle every aspect of the society into which
they were indoctrinated.
The latest drop at AmandaLandExports may look like it's a game, but reminds us that fascism
certainly is not.
Get your Fascist or Not Your Friends tees, stickers, and more at AmandaLandExports.com.
Bye!
!